[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
“The mysterious unknown.”
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
What’s that?
-It's something Ging left with me.
-What?
He asked me to give this to you
when you became a Hunter.
[Gon] So Dad left this for me?
REPLY X FROM X DAD
[narrator]
Three mysterious items were inside the box
that had been sealed with Nen...
One of these items, an old cassette tape,
gave Gon a long-awaited opportunity:
the chance to hear his father’s voice
for the first time.
[Ging on tape] Hey... Gon.
So, you became a Hunter too, huh?
This is my dad’s voice...
[Ging] Anyway...
I have a question for you.
Do you...
want to see me?
[gasps]
[Ging] If you do,
keep listening.
If you don’t,
just press the stop button.
I'm guessing that's a "yes".
But I’ll ask you one more time.
Are you sure?
Hunters are selfish creatures.
We’re willing to sacrifice
anything and everything
to get what we want.
If you just think
it would be nice to see me...
stop the tape here.
I’ll give you a minute.
What do you think?
[chuckles softly]
[bird squawks]
[tired exhale]
[Ging sighs]
[Ging] You want to see me that much, huh?
Well... I don’t want to see you.
[both gasp]
[Ging] Honestly, I don’t know
how I could face you.
After all...
I walked away from being a parent
for purely selfish reasons.
I’m not a decent guy...
[birds tweeting]
[Ging] I don’t have any way of knowing
how much time will pass
before you listen to this tape.
I figure it’ll be at least ten years.
But it doesn’t matter.
There’s one thing that will never change.
I’ll always be...
the guy I am.
Bo!
[growls]
[roaring]
[Ging] As you sit there,
listening to this tape,
I’m sure I’ll be off,
horsing around somewhere.
If you still want to see me,
find me.
But like I said...
I don’t want to see you.
If I hear you coming,
I’m gonna bolt.
Catch me if you can.
You are a Hunter now, aren’t you?
[Killua] Hmm.
If you thought your dad
would be easy to track,
then you better think again.
-[Gon] Hey, wait.
-Hmm?
-Ging’s still there. Let it play.
-Oh.
[Ging] Oh...
there’s one more thing
I forgot to mention.
It’s... about your mother.
[gasps]
[Ging] If you want to know more,
keep listening.
If you don’t then--
Are you sure?
Uh-huh.
But what about the rest of it?
What if he left you another clue?
No way. Not him.
I can feel it.
And like I said before...
I do have a mom:
Aunt Mito.
[Killua] I see.
[grunts] Hey, are you hungry?
I’ll go get us something to eat.
[Killua] Sure.
-Hey, Gon!
-Huh?
The tape started moving all by itself!
Wait, what?!
Is that aura?
It’s Nen!
And it’s rewinding the tape!
Nen?
He’s close! He’s gotta be!
No. Over ten years ago
he imbued it with aura,
so it would start rewinding
the minute that it stopped!
But why?
I’ve no idea.
Look! Now it’s recording!
Wait, I think I get it.
He’s erasing his voice!
What?!
[Gon grunts]
It won’t stop, dammit!
[Killua] It’s still going!
Even when I unplug it?
I’m breaking it.
Sorry!
Crap!
It’s no use.
The Nen’s protecting it!
[banging]
-[banging above]
-Huh?
[grunts]
It looks like it’s finished.
[sighs]
[Killua] Look! Now it’s recording!
Wait, I think I get it.
He’s erasing his voice!
[Gon] What?!
[Gon trying to press button
on recording]
The duplicate cassette tape
was completely wiped, too.
I just don’t get why he would go through
all this trouble.
He probably didn’t want
to leave any clues or anything for us.
[Gon] What do you mean?
You can extract a whole lot of information
from a simple audio clip.
[Gon] Really?
You can determine about
how tall the speaker likely is,
their weight, their age,
diseases, facial features,
even a psych profile.
Oh...
From the noise in the background
you can even determine
their exact location.
But that’s not what he was worried about.
There’s something else.
What are you talking about?
His Nen abilities.
[gasps]
There might be a Nen user somewhere
who can analyze data
better than a machine.
I bet there is.
They can hear your voice
and it would tell them everything
they’d ever need to know about you.
I see...
Your dad is tough.
Like, really tough.
[grunts]
This is useless.
Lucky it wasn’t the only clue.
We’ve still got two more left.
The ring and the memory card.
The ring probably won’t help,
but the memory card might.
Yeah. But it’s smaller than a normal one.
You think we’re gonna need
special hardware for it?
Wait-- You mean you can’t tell?
This is only designed to work with the JS.
What’s a JS?
A gaming console called the Joystation
from three generations back.
Man, don’t you know anything?
If this island still has cassette players,
there’s gotta be an old console
around here somewhere.
There a toy store here?
I’m pretty sure there is.
-Okay. Hold on.
-Huh?
Oh! Where are you going?
To the toy store.
Huh?
-[Gon] It’s outside the port!
-Huh?
[Killua] Got it!
Have a safe trip, okay?
[Gon] Oh... so this is a Joystation...
This takes me back.
I used to play it a lot.
There were a bunch of cult classics
made for it.
Hmm...
Then is this memory card a cult classic?
‘Cause I don’t see a title on it anywhere.
You’ve never played
any video games, have you?
That’s pretty weird.
Seriously?
That’s not a game disc.
It holds a game's memory data.
I guess that means
we can’t use it to play.
[Killua] Nope.
You’re supposed to put the disc in here.
But if you insert the memory card
and power it on without a game inside,
you can see all the different games
that are using that memory.
Oh, okay.
[Killua] Huh...
It looks like there’s only one game
saved on it.
It’s called Greed Island.
[Gon] Greed Island?
Well, anyway,
there are lots of saves on here.
It might be pointless
but I’ll try to copy the data.
[Joystation voice] Copying Greed Island.
Okay.
[computer beeps]
What are you doing?
Searching online.
We know what it’s called...
I’m looking for a store that sells it.
0 MATCHES
What? No way!
Not a single match?
That means it’s all sold out?
But I can’t find any used copies, either.
Even a totally sold-out game
would be out there somewhere...
Well... I guess it’s possible
this game was never actually
on the market.
What does that mean?
Maybe it was an indie game or something
and it never got distribution.
Or it could even be a game
that was banned from sale for some reason.
I’ll keep looking and see what I can find.
Got it.
Well, it turns out it was actually
sold through legitimate channels.
It says “Greed Island...
A hunting game exclusively...
for Hunters.”
For Hunters, huh?
What the--!
Look at that price tag!
Five hundred and eighty million?!
-It’s five point eight billion!
-Say what?!
That’s crazy!
No game has ever cost that much money!
Only a hundred copies were made.
That’s not very many, is it?
No, it’s practically nothing!
Which means the developers
were really cocky!
But it makes sense.
The price tag is ridiculous,
unless, of course, you’re a Hunter.
That explains how they sold out.
Do the developers have any more
left in stock?
Good question.
I guess it’s worth a shot to ask them.
[representative] I’m sorry,
the game you’re inquiring about
is no longer in stock.
And unfortunately, there are no plans
to re-release it at this time.
Oh, okay. Thank you.
That was a dead end.
Then... we’ll have to find someone
who has a copy
and see if they’ll let us have it.
You’re right.
So first we’re gonna need
to locate a seller.
Why don’t we post an ad
on a reverse auction website.
But... where will we get the money?
We’ll pool our money from the Arena
and that gets us
to just over eight hundred million.
We still need another five billion.
-[Killua] Not necessarily.
-Huh?
With these private deals,
the seller has all the power.
And they usually set a higher price
than what they originally paid for it.
[Gon] Then... it’ll cost even more?
Probably.
[both] Hmm...
[Gon] Well... we can still post a want ad,
just in case.
Yeah. But I doubt anybody
is gonna click on it.
“We are looking for a game.
Does anybody have
Greed Island for sale?
Price... negotiable.”
[both gasp]
[both] Oh!
[gasps] Wow, look!
We already have more than 10,000 hits!
I don’t believe it!
I thought so.
It looks like they’re all trying
to unload counterfeit copies on us.
Considering the high price,
we really should’ve seen this coming.
This isn’t gonna work.
No way we can verify
every one of these offers.
Besides, what’s the point
if we can’t even tell
if it’s the real game?
Then what do you think we should do now?
Well, we need to uncover
a lot more information.
Let’s dig deeper online.
But I’m really no expert
in all that stuff.
So, who do we know
who’s into gaming and the internet?
[gasps]
I... think I might know somebody...
[Gon] Huh?
In fact, he might even own
a copy of Greed Island already.
Really? You think so?
Guess I’ll ask him...
but I really don’t wanna.
Who is it? Who is it?
Hey. Gotoh? It’s Killua.
Mister Gotoh?
Yeah. Yeah, I’m doing great.
Now? Who cares where I am?
If I tell you, Mom’s gonna find out
sooner or later.
Anyway...
can you get Piggy for me?
Who’s Piggy?
[pig grunts]
[Milluki] What?!
Killua wants to talk to me?
Screw that.
Tell him I stepped out or something.
Shut up! You’re lying!
He hasn’t left the house in ages!
You go tell him if he doesn’t
pick up the phone in ten seconds,
I’ll break all of his figurines!
[irked grunt]
All right, all right.
Just put him on.
Hey, Kil.
If you even think
about laying a finger on my collection,
I’m gonna kill you.
Chill out, bro.
I was only kidding.
You’re so scary when you get mad!
Wait, your brother?
What the hell do you want, anyway?
Hurry up, I’m busy.
Oh yeah. Greed Island?
I’ve heard of it.
It’s a super-rare game.
Why? You’ve never been interested
in rare games.
Do you own a copy?
[Milluki] No, I don't.
-[sighs]
-[Milluki] I wanted one,
but I was five when it went on sale,
and I didn’t have any money.
But I heard there were
over twenty thousand requests
and only a hundred copies.
Because of that each copy
costs a whole lot of Jenny;
about five point eight bil.
I tried to track one down
right after the thrill wore off,
but I couldn’t even find an owner.
It’s legendary for all kinds of reasons.
So, what’s the deal?
You looking for a copy or what?
-Kinda.
-[Milluki] Well, forget it!
It’s impossible.
Even I had to give up.
Oh? You had to admit defeat
‘cause it was too much for you to handle?
[annoyed growl]
That was years ago.
I’ve got a few leads now, smart guy.
But considering how much effort
it would take,
not to mention money,
it’s not worth my time.
So...
What were those leads
you were talking about?
[Milluki] Yeah, right.
Like I’d tell you for free.
If I had a Greed Island memory card,
would you... reconsider?
[Milluki] Huh?
What are you saying?
[Killua] I just happened to get my hands
on a memory card, that’s all.
I figured with your skills,
you could analyze the data
and reverse engineer
the game itself, right?
[Milluki] Is that true?
You better not be lying.
[Killua] I never lie.
Not when I’m making deals.
[Milluki] Okay, fine.
I have two leads.
Wait a minute.
Not over the phone!
Don’t worry, Kil.
If somebody is eavesdropping,
this information won’t do them any good.
Okay. First lead...
Yeah. Yeah. I see.
Okay, got it.
I’ll send it to you in the usual way.
Sorry... but I kinda had to promise him
the copy of the memory card in exchange.
Sure.
It’s just a copy anyway, so I don’t mind.
Well in return,
I got two leads that sound pretty solid.
One’s a website.
It’s only accessible to Hunters,
which is no problem for you.
I’m almost positive we can find
more leads on Greed Island there.
[Gon] Really?
That means
I get to use my Hunter’s License!
Stupid!
If you use your home computer,
they’re gonna know your address!
You really want bad guys
showing up on this island
to steal your Hunter’s license?
Oh. Yeah, I forgot.
You’ve gotta use public computers
for this kind of thing,
like at a hotel or a ‘net café.
Well... there’s no rush.
I still don’t even know the address.
Once my brother gets the memory card,
he said he’d send it to me.
Or lead two:
The Yorknew City auction.
What?! Hold on, isn’t Yorknew City--?
Yeah.
We’re supposed
to meet Kurapika and Leorio there.
Also,
they’re holding the world’s greatest
auction there in September.
My brother said it’s probably a hoax,
but there’s a rumor going around
that someone’s gonna be auctioning off
dozens of copies.
Then maybe... that someone is Ging!
Yeah. So maybe it’s not a rumor.
It just might be credible!
[Gon] But we’re gonna need
a crazy amount of money to buy a copy.
Yeah, you’re right about that.
[Gon] I guess...
it really was our destiny
to go to Yorknew City.
[Milluki] Hmm...
Battera, the tycoon,
is offering 17 billion for Greed Island
and 50 billion more for a memory card
with a complete saved game on it.
That's truly legendary.
[chuckles] Interesting...
I’ll put an end to this legend myself.
[Gon] Wow!
This is incredible!
What’s the big occasion?
You probably won’t be back to visit
for a little while.
[gasps]
Aunt Mito...
Who knows
when you’ll get a chance to eat again?
Better fill up while you can.
[chuckles softly]
Mm-hmm.
[chuckles]
[Gon] All right!
[Gon and Killua] Thank you for the food!
[indistinct chatter]
[Gon] Aunt Mito!
So long!
I’m gonna go find Ging, I promise!
And after I meet him,
I’m gonna come back to the island, okay?
Bye! Take care! I’ll miss you!
[narrator] Ging told Gon to find him,
leaving a riddle behind
as a clue to his whereabouts.
In order to solve that riddle
and meet his father,
Gon leaves home once again
with his friend, Killua, by his side,
and sets sail for Yorknew City.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Ging!
He’s my dad,
and I became a Hunter to find him!
Oh, yeah, so what do you think
your dad wants, anyway?
I really don't know, but as soon as
I find him, I’ll be sure to ask!
[Gon] Next time:
"Wish x And x Promise"!
Go to sleep or you’ll be late.
[Killua] Who, me? Nah. I don’t need sleep.
[Gon] Try to get plenty of rest, everyone!